<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./docbook.css" type="text/css"?>
<chapter xml:id="authorization" xml:lang="en" version="5.0"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd">

    <title>Authorization</title>
    <section xml:id="auth_scheme">
        <title>Role scheme</title>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>Authorization role scheme</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="./images/auth_scheme.png" align="center" width="90%" scalefit="1"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
        </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="auth_role_desc">
        <title>Roles description</title>
        <section xml:id="auth_visitor">
            <title>Visitor</title>
            <para>
                Visitor (user without any roles assigned) permissions:
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Use VTL Editor, save files on disk, load files from disk.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Use SDMX registries, import Data Structure Definitions.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>View all domains and items in the Domain Repository.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                Visitor doesn’t have personal storage and can’t save items in the VRM repository.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="auth_user">
            <title>Domain user</title>
            <para>
                Domain user additional permissions:
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Save/edit/delete items in the personal storage in the VRM repository.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Edit and execute all items in the assigned domains.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                Domain user can publish items from personal storage to Domain Repository
                Items edited in the Domain Repository are saved as a patch version indicated by third part in version number.
                They are considered draft by default — marked as non-final versions.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="auth_manager">
            <title>Domain manager</title>
            <para>
                Domain manager additional permissions:
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Delete all items in the assigned domains.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>View the Recycle Bin for the assigned domains and delete items permanently.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Add and remove users in the assigned domains and groups.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                Domain manager can’t create or remove domains and groups, and doesn’t have right to change group roles.
            </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="auth_admin">
            <title>Administrator</title>
            <para>
                <emphasis role="bold">IMPORTANT! </emphasis>
                The first user logged in to the VRM application will automatically be granted administrator rights by system.
                Please take this into consideration.
            </para>
            <para>
                Administrator additional permissions:
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>View the Recycle Bin for the Domain Repository and delete items permanently.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Add, edit and remove users, domains, and groups.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Assign and remove user and group roles.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Add and remove users in all the domains and groups.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="auth_user_profile">
        <title>User profile</title>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>An exemplary view of actual user profile.</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="./images/auth_user_profile.png" align="center" width="90%" scalefit="1"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            Access to the user profile is always available in the upper right corner of the application after pressing the button(1).
            A view(2) will open allowing the user to view all information related to his account.
            The user cannot edit his data himself, he must ask for it a user with appropriate permissions in the application.
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>