<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./docbook.css" type="text/css"?>
<chapter xml:id="domain_repository" xml:lang="en" version="5.0"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd">

    <title>Domain Repository</title>
    <para>
        Domain repository works identically to personal repository,
        except that it is a public repository available only to users of a given domain.
        Just creating a domain doesn't create a repository - it doesn't exists initially.
        It is only created when first file is published by any user of that domain.
    </para>

    <section xml:id="file_publication">
        <title>File publication</title>
        <para>
            Publication is a tool/feature that is used to <emphasis role="italic">publish current version of a given file</emphasis>.
            It means that published file is a perfect copy only until original or published file version change after publication.
        </para>
        <para>
            Publication of files in current version of application is made from level of personal repository.
            Publishing a file creates a <emphasis role="italic">copy of current version of script file</emphasis>, and then saves file in the repository of selected domain.
            If this is the <emphasis role="italic">first file</emphasis> published for this domain – a repository will be created.
        </para>
        <para>
            The version of published file is always "0.1.0". It can be manually updated when needed.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="recycle_bin">
        <title>Recycle Bin</title>
        <para>
            Due to public characteristics of domain repository, it is secured with a two-step deletion of files.
            Unlike a personal repository, files are not deleted permanently by domain user.
            They temporarily land in the <emphasis role="bold">Recycle Bin</emphasis>.
            In this state, they are only visible for domain manager and admin through tools made available to them only.
            Depending on their decision, it can be restored or permanently deleted (no data recovery possible).
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">IMPORTANT!</emphasis>
            Due to fact that after recovery/deletion operation, state of file is not updated - it is required to refresh
            domain repository by calling context menu on it (right-click) and selecting <emphasis role="italic">"Refresh"</emphasis> option.
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>