<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./docbook.css" type="text/css"?>
<chapter xml:id="vtl_editor" xml:lang="en" version="5.0"
         xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd">

    <title>VTL Editor</title>

    <para>In the <emphasis role="bold">VTL Editor</emphasis> you have available all the following functionalities for the files:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>Create VTL file</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Save file</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Open file</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Search and replace</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Syntax highlighting for VTL elements</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Autocomplete VTL syntax elements</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Display context help regarding VTL syntax elements and snippets</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Check VTL grammar for the file</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Display syntax errors with details on the list in the error panel</para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <section xml:id="create_vtl_file">
        <title>Creating VTL File</title>
        <para>After opening application, you have the document opened, with empty code field in the editor.
            You can add new code or upload existing<emphasis role="bold">VTL file</emphasis> from the storage with using in menu option
            <emphasis role="bold">'Open file'</emphasis>. You can save the file at any time, <emphasis role="bold">VTL Editor</emphasis> also has autosave option, so you can go
            back to adding content even after closing the application.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="save_vtl_file">
        <title>Saving VTL File</title>
        <para>You can also add changes to the tab with the code. If you click on the <emphasis role="bold">'Save file'</emphasis> option in main menu, you have possibility to
            save <emphasis role="bold">VTL file</emphasis> to local storage at any time. Additionally, if you have unsaved changes and application is closed without saving
            file, after reopening editor, it will restore last version of used document. File changes and settings from the last opening are saved automatically and when the
            application is run, last
            saved version is automatically loaded.
        </para>

        <para>Procedure of saving <emphasis role="bold">VTL Editor</emphasis> contents to local storage:
        </para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Choose icon <emphasis role="bold">'Save'</emphasis> in main menu.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>If the file has a path added on your computer, the file will be saved or if not, you will see a
                    window and you should add the path to save the file.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>You see success/error message for saving file.</para>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="load_vtl_file">
        <title>Opening VTL File</title>
        <para>
            If you click on the ‘<emphasis role="bold">Open file</emphasis>’ option in main menu, you have possibility to load file from an external file into the editor.
            Aditionally, you have possibility to have opened more than one file. New files will be opened in the new carts, after opening new cart in browser.
        </para>

        <para>Procedure of opening text <emphasis role="bold">VTL file</emphasis> from local storage:
        </para>
        <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Go to main menu.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Choose icon
                    <emphasis role="bold">'Open file'</emphasis>
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>You have two options for upload a text <emphasis role="bold">VTL file</emphasis> from local storage:
                </para>
                <itemizedlist mark="circle">
                    <listitem>
                        <para>choosing button Add file on the pop-up and uploads file from the path to the file on
                            local storage,
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>dragging the file and dropping it in the appropriate field, marked with a dashed line,
                            on the main screen Procedure of opening
                            <emphasis role="bold">VTL text file.</emphasis>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="search_and_replace">
        <title>Search and Replace</title>
        <para>You can search for text in a file by pressing <emphasis role="bold">Ctrl + F</emphasis>. This will open up the Find panel on the
            bottom:

            Enter your search term here and press <emphasis role="bold">Enter</emphasis>. You can navigate between matches by
            continuously hitting <emphasis role="bold">Enter</emphasis> (or <emphasis role="bold">Shift + Enter</emphasis> to go backwards). The searched phrase is highlighted
            in the editor and scrollbar.
            If you want to replace a match, expand the <emphasis role="bold">Search widget</emphasis> to display the <emphasis role="bold">Replace text box</emphasis> and
            enter the text you want to replace it with in the Replace input field. Then hit <emphasis role="bold">Enter</emphasis> to replace the
            match and keep hitting <emphasis role="bold">Enter</emphasis> to replace each subsequent match or <emphasis role="bold">Ctrl+Alt+Enter</emphasis> to
            immediately replace all. The searched phrase is highlighted in the editor and scrollbar.
            Highlighting a word in the code editor will highlight all other matches in the file which makes it
            easier to check where a variable or function is being used. You can replace all in one file or
            replace a single change.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="syntax_highligting">
        <title>Syntax Highlighting</title>
        <para>
            You have possibility to switch color to a different <emphasis role="bold">syntax highlighting for VTL elements</emphasis> in the code editor. You can edit your
            preferences by clicking on <emphasis role="bold">Settings/Color theme</emphasis> and choosing one option to display the theme preferences drop-down:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist mark="circle">
            <listitem>
                <literallayout>VTL</literallayout>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <literallayout>Light</literallayout>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <literallayout>Dark</literallayout>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <literallayout>High Contrast Dark</literallayout>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="autocomplete">
        <title>Autocomplete</title>
        <para>The editor supports autocomplete of VTL elements and when you type a letter or hit <emphasis role="bold">Ctrl+Space</emphasis>,
            you will see a list of autocomplete suggestions. After choosing name from the list, by using mouse cursor or
            selecting with keyboard, selected keyword is added to the code.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="display_content_help">
        <title>Context Help</title>
        <para>Context help regarding <emphasis role="bold">VTL syntax elements and snippet</emphasis> are displayed in the editor, after
            moving the cursor over the name and selecting the <emphasis role="bold">'i'</emphasis> icon in the line with the selected name.
            <emphasis role="bold">Context help</emphasis>
            is displayed during typing, as shown in the example:
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="check_grammar">
        <title>VTL Syntax Check</title>
        <para>For the content of the files, is checked structure. In case of syntax errors, they are underlined in
            application and details are added on the bottom error panel. Additionally, after moving your
            cursor to the place with error, you will see the error details.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section xml:id="display_errors">
        <title>Syntax Errors</title>
        <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">VTL Editor</emphasis>
            displays of potential errors and warnings in a dedicated section of the page and on
            the bottom panel. As default blue panel is collapsed. After press arrow on the left, you will see
            the list in the panel with line, column and message of <emphasis role="bold">syntax or grammar error</emphasis>. In the code, the
            position with error has red underline.
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>